What just happened?
Kawachi
Yeah. Right.
I was just about to get up.
Really? Okay.
Stop worrying already.
We'll begin negotiations with them next week, okay?
Later.
Last night, my grandfather on my mother's side passed away.
Were the people in that dream...
...Granddad and Mum?
Apparently, he had fallen out of touch with his relatives.
Geez. The first time I've been back here in forever, and it's for a funeral.
Usagi
Drop
Ashita no koto wa wakaranai
明日のことはわからない
I can't tell what'll come tomorrow.
Kore tte gisei to wa chigau
これって犠牲とは違う
This is different than making a sacrifice.
Nanika ga chigau
何かが違う
Something about it is different.
Batsu geemu ja nante omowanai
罰ゲームじゃなんて思わない
And I don't think of it as some sort of forfeit.
...tte nande na no ka wakaranai
...ってなんでなのか分からない
So I just don't get why.
Chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと釈然としないけど
I can't quite wrap my head around it,
Kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
君の存在今大事だなんてもんじゃない
but your existence is now much more than just important to me.
Owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
終わらないことなんてこの世のどこにもない
There's nothing in this world that doesn't come to an end.
Naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
泣くのは辛いんじゃないの
I don't cry because I'm hurting.
Ai no sweet drops sweet drops
愛の sweet drops sweet drops
They're the sweet, sweet drops of love!
Zutto yume mite mitai ne
ずっと夢見てみたいね
I want to go on dreaming forever, you know?
Motto yasashiku shitai ne
もっと優しくしたいね
I want to try and be more gentle, you know?
Kimi to iraretara happy
君といられたらhappy
If I can be with you, I'm happy.
Onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って強いね
Girls are really strong, aren't they?
Dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど時々弱いね
But sometimes, they can be really weak, you know?
Bokura no negai wa happy happy happy
僕らの願いは happy happy happy
Our wishes are happy, happy, happy.
Sonna hibi mo happy
そんな日々も happy
And our days will be just as happy!
Just wanna make you happy!
I'm here.
Oh, Daikichi. You're early.
You can leave your bag in Granddad's room.
Right.
By the way, I saw a girl in the garden...
I don't remember her. Did Haruko's kid look like that?
That isn't Reina-chan.
Then whose kid is she?
Geez. This kitchen is so awkward...
What should I do now?
He went pretty peacefully for someone who lived to be 79.
Apparently, that girl is your grandfather's illegitimate child.
Huh!?
Granddad's kid!?
He never told me anything about that!
And apparently, his lover took off, too.
Lover? The guy was 79, right?
It's so embarrassing and shameful.
Then that makes her your little sister, right?
And my aunt, I guess.
It's not a joke!
You're thirty years old now! Try to be a bit more sensitive!
You went peacefully, didn't you, Granddad?
How much should I give?
That's entirely up to you. Give as much or as little as you wish.
But surely, you must expect a certain amount.
Really, however much you wish to give would be appreciated.
Though the custom these days is to have some Buddhist scriptures read...
...and a posthumous Buddhist name conferred on the dead.
She said it'd cost between 400,000 and 500,000 yen.
That's a fair amount.
Hello. It's been a long time.
Oh, Daikichi. It's been a while.
Have you been keeping busy?
Well, yeah...
Too busy to make time for his dear mother, who longs to see him.
Didn't even make it back for New Year.
Wait, Reina!
Hey, Reina!
Haruko!
Oh, Dai-chan. It's been a while.
Mum!
Reina!
Got you!
Be a good girl and sit quietly, okay?
Don't want to!
What is it?
Nothing...
You really are just like your grandfather.
Daikichi, did you hear?
Yeah, Mum told me before.
I wonder.
I'm sure my brother was lonely, since he lived on his own, but...
Apparently, they found a Baby Book...
...with the name "Rin" in it.
But pulling something like that at the age of 79...?
Well, putting aside whether or not he's her father,
you've got to hand it to the old guy.
Daikichi, can you get the cushions out of the closet?
What do you want?
Hey, hey!
I'll trade you!
No! Leave it like that.
I did it!
Hey! Look, look!
Reina, don't run around!
Well done!
Is it pretty?
Of course! You're awfully good at cat's cradle, Reina-chan!
Try and do a four step ladder next!
My, my. Reina-chan... Pass it to me a moment.
Poo bomb!
Stop that, Reina!
Uncle. Uncle!
You should go to sleep.
I'll handle the incense for a bit.
Right.
Hey, don't sleep there!
I'll go and get some rest there.
What about the incense?
Daikichi says he'll keep an eye on it.
Come on!
Keep an eye on my brother, okay?
You should go through and sleep, too.
I'm fine.
You look awful.
Kaga Souichi
Well, then, everyone.
Please say your last good-byes.
Say hello to your mother for me.
Granddad...
I'll see you soon enough.
Reina, time to go.
Coming!
It's time to say good-bye to Granddad.
Okay.
A field of flowers!
Stop that!
No! I'm going to make a field of flowers!
I want to make one!
You should come and say good-bye, too.
Put these on Granddad.
Hey!
Bellflowers...
TL Note: In Japanese, bellflowers are 'Rindou'.
Granddad's favourite flowers...
He'd be happiest with these flowers, right?
Is he never going to wake up?
No. He'll never wake up again.
You really are his kid, aren't you?
Baby Book
So what happened to this "Yoshii Masako"?
I don't think tracking down someone who abandoned their child...
...will really lead to much good.
How irresponsible.
And my brother stubbornly refused to say a word about it, too.
Watch it!
That girl can't talk!
She's such a pain.
And she hasn't even lost her baby teeth!
She can, too!
And she's not a pain!
She can't talk!
So I'm so bored!
Here. Take them all and go away!
You're like a sweet shop owner!
Sorry, Dai-chan.
Never mind any long-term plans,
who's going to take care of her now?
I can't. We have a shop to run.
If she were just a little less strange...
And it looks like she hasn't even started to speak yet.
Mum, you're at home all the time.
Can't you take her for a bit?
T-There's no way I can do that!
I don't have the time for something like that!
Do you even know how difficult it is to raise a child?
And how much I've already sacrificed?
If you can't properly take care of her, it'd be less cruel not to bother at all.
Aren't we supposed to be finding somebody to take her?
It's not like you're planning to do anything yourself, Onii-chan.
Try to look at things a bit more realistically.
Besides, we don't even know whether she really is Granddad's child.
Nothing to say, right? Bet you haven't even thought it through.
For now,
I suggest contacting facilities that will take her off our hands immediately.
What?
Rin!
Want to come stay with me?
Hey, Daikichi!
Onii-chan!
Gramps, I'm hungry.
G-Gramps?
Don't call me that!
You're the one who's my aunt!
Nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
A sunny Sunday's early afternoon;
Kyou wa doko e yukou?
今日はどこへ行こう？
where should we go today?
Kayoinareta itsumo no michi ga
通い慣れたいつもの道が
The same old road that I'm so used to walking on...
Mabushiku kagayaite mieru
眩しく 輝いて見える
...shines with a dazzling light.
Terasu atatakai taiyou to
照らす暖かい太陽と
If I have the warm sunlight shining down on me...
Tonari ni kimi ga ireba...
隣に君がいれば
...and you by my side...
Whoa! High, high, high!
Hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
My feelings are ready to burst forth.
Utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
Sing out, lai lai lai!
Koe wa doko made mo
声はどこまでも
My voice reaches every corner of the earth.
Mou high high high!
もう high high high!
I'm already high, high, high!
Maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Riding the whirling winds...
Utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
Sing out, lai lai lai!
Koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
My voice swoops up and down with me.
Is it good?
Yeah.
Seconds?
There's nothing left to go with the rice.
I'll make rice balls.
I don't have the tools to make them, either.
Salt!
Salt?
Hey! It's still hot!
Hey, look!
But it'll have a gentle flavour.
Here you go, Gramps!
Sorry. Daikichi!
"Daikichi" sounds weird, too.
It's good.